I've called the Board of Directors here to meet the University Council for today, June 3rd, 2020, 5.
Public hearing on the proposed fiscal year 25, 26 budget.
We ask questions, or about budget time to ask.
I don't really know.
Yes, we do.
I'll ask all of you for anyone to ask questions on the 25, 26 budget.
10, that's a common section.
That's what to say well here.
I'm three.
Public input.
I'm just going to the personal period.
So we have nine.
Four.
Plains list.
Second.
Don't hold.
Hi.
Peace out.
Jones.
Marker.
Five.
I'm in a memorandum of understanding for the Audit County for the market for 20.
Is that?
To the approve.
Second.
Hold.
Five.
Jones.
Peace out.
Parker.
Six.
fiscal year 25, 26 budget message.
Resolution regarding.
To see my amount of home budget.
Last Tuesday.
Our discussion about budget with the power.
There's been change to the numbers of a bit and I want to make sure I got all the changes
that I could for again.
You have four documents setting for me.
I'll roll to the top.
One is the budget summary that somehow ny.
The two are a bit one of those two.
But one of the best on it is the same 100-puzzle resolution that we have done from the past.
The moment the enemy is there, it's a different type of resolution.
We can talk about that from there.
I refer to the following things.
And I'm talking about your opinions to the number change.
So last Tuesday, we said, we're on a budget for you.
We're going to $2003,000.
Well, that's changed to $100,000.
We're going to $50,000.
$10,000.
That is maybe a $10,000 of that.
It was made up with the grant of the library.
It was just a word.
So when I started to get that in,
then the other two of them are in one change.
And then another experience with another fund.
The rest of the West and the West for a while now, so I already know that this is going to be here.
This is the city centre to move on to move money within the same time.
We have 30 funders, especially its own real business.
In Australia, one of the funds in Japan.
If that 102 or 500 million to have to either 1,000 got larger.
So we got new money.
We got more answers.
We have new year.
You would see that.
The two types of amendments should see.
The investor resolution with the end of the comment allows the city manager to agree.
We just have the authority to approve all money.
Which if we get, if we go that route then we put like a form in the packet.
So everybody would see it.
It's just, so I'm not just kind of confusing when we like, we get insurance claim.
We get money from the insurance company.
We bring it to the board and say we're getting another $20,000 to fix this car.
And then we come before you.
I mean, it's just kind of a, yeah, we've done it.
Where we are.
We get a grant.
We get money and the grants we have to come here to get it to.
You've got a lot of responsibility anyway.
Do you really want more?
It's a, it's really whatever the board wants to do.
I mean, there be a ceiling on this.
I can amount that we would succeed.
Council can pass it anyway they want.
The form of government that you have is a form of government where the council gives
oversight.
The city manager runs the day-to-day operations and this.
I do know that other cities with this form of government lose this kind of a budget model.
So my, my thought process behind my question was around protection of Tyler.
If there was if we put a cap on his level of what he was able to move without council approval,
then he's covered as far as what we spelled out.
And then if it goes above a certain amount, then maybe it does need a little bit more in debt
review from the council's perspective.
That sounds good to me.
That's, that's, that's my thought.
It's just, I think, most business.
I don't have a number in mind.
So going back to my travel days.
Anything over like 25,000, I think, if I'm not wrong.
was anything over 25,000 had to be reviewed by the business committee there.
And that, to me, that feels, that's fine.
I mean, it can be 50, I don't know what the number is, whatever we decided is.
But whatever that level of comfort that you feel, I think,
because as you get into moving bigger dollars, like if you're moving a hundred thousand dollars,
you want to make sure everybody's eyes are on it and you're not.
That's, I know the county's got a budget to where they can,
the volunteer fire departments can use, like up to $20,000 a year
without having to have a permanent county commissioners.
Is that where years of that right now anyway?
Yeah, $20,000.
They make it the same.
Again, I just am trying to protect Tyler.
As the 20,000, everybody has you.
Everyone's wanting to, we have to ask you to produce some claims.
There were around the 20,000.
You have less, but I was calling you in table.
That's when you do approval in this or whatever.
So, as far as that levels concerned, I know the goal of this is to keep from
inundating the council with tiny money moves that are written significant.
Is 20,000 that limit or is it 25?
Where is it that we can start at 20 and see how it goes?
And we can change it later if we fill it.
It don't happen ever week.
Now, I mean, 20 is fine.
We can start at 20 and see how it goes.
It's always a weird process to me.
I mean, you know, that we're like, hey, we got this grant for $3,000 at the library.
Yeah, I know I, I 100% agree with that.
I'm really waiting on us to approve it.
That every one of the next council meeting is going to be.
Yeah.
I like the 20,000 cat for first.
And then we can always approve something different.
Exactly.
It goes the first year and talk about it.
But you get a topic for next year.
You still provide us updates on grants and stuff, so they can still provide us.
Yeah.
And I'll ask Jill and finance to like make a foreigner, whatever that we'll just put it in the pocket and just say this is, you know, what we've done for the.
Crystal from your perspective, does that seem.
This is our.
Or if it's too much to think that like there's not enough bias on the situation.
You know, I mean, like just too much too many moves.
And then.
I mean, it's like that.
Yeah.
And like I said, I don't want to tell her to fill over well.
I mean, I know you got a bunch on your plate anyway.
So I just don't.
I don't mind if you're looking around.
Thank you.
That was rude.
You know, and there's a kind of change in somebody.
Quick.
everybody on the budget. I mean we've sat down on a staff. We've kind of
much of stuff. You know we've realized we've got to do more with less people.
We all work together to get here. I mean at Jill worked hard, Jennifer worked hard,
Chris worked hard. I mean I'm going to wrote an excellent 12 page, you know, budget
message. I kind of look at this as like, you know, last year we got all of our
grants this year. We're actually putting our grants in action, you know.
I think we can approve it. I think we can approve it. A lot of that.
This has been. Obviously it's not. I mean I haven't spent more money because
I mean I don't mean I like to build beautiful things but I mean it's like
we're like bringing so much money so. I don't believe that because you're tight.
Look at his staff. Everybody's like, look at his eye bed.
Yeah, thank you. Look at his.
Can we approve this without a new
with the $20,000 dollar debt or make a motion to approve this with the $20,000.
Yeah. I'll make a motion approved. The changes were requested with the $20,000.
That's all second. Which resolution were we going to do?
That's good news.
I went back to new resolution.
That. I did.
Nunkle.
Jones, aye.
Jones. Aye.
Hey, Seth. Hi.
Barnes, aye. Parker.
Aye.
No, please.
We renew.
Make a motion or we approve the rainy day certification.
Aye.
Barnes, aye.
Hi, local.
Hi.
Jones.
Perfect.
Hi.
Seven.
To us in Buffalo Action, we're guarding proposed memorandum of understanding between the
City of Mioente and the All Tribe for purposes of entering and seeing agreement
necessary to obtain special law enforcement permission for our Police Office Chief
seam.
Sure.
I clarify that was for the approval of the budget and the resolution right?
Yes.
Thank you.
Sorry.
So, as most of you are aware, one of the issues that we do with here in Miami, the first step in the process of trying to solve this through a system where you're working on developing the same environment that all of the tribes sort of apply to you for pause, wait for to start, and then if we have a agreement.
I think that's great because I feel like these last few weeks we've had some pretty intense moments of crime.
But this, I think, will be able to be, I think, my dad and I added it up and there's over a hundred of some officers hired
from the city and the tribal entities and the time to get somebody to the site.
I think this would be a great way to increase that gap of time to get those people.
But we had situations where we had to wait for the IA and it's been three months.
Right.
That's the situation today, where there was a domestic and progress.
We tried to work as a change.
Thanks.
I was going to be my next question.
Mr. Court piece.
Thanks for kind of finding it.
I'll make a motion.
Wait.
Second.
Is that James?
Hi.
Thank you.
Hey.
The discussion on the criteria of an honorary degree naming in the city of mine.
Yeah.
Let me get out of my paperwork.
Sorry.
I missed you still.
It's some drinks over here.
It's a real way.
So board.
Tonight.
Everyone's probably going to head up about honorary street naming.
And I personally think we should have a criteria for how we do it.
Because to me, it's like we want to name a street after somebody that's never lived in my island.
But maybe they've done something.
I mean, or, you know, Kevin has promised me a crit.
So I mean, it's like.
I just think that a, you know, bus, bus, bus means statue.
If I get the trucker out of grand.
So small one.
He said it would be a small one.
I like a small one.
But you know, a lot of cities.
A lot of cities have straight naming criteria.
Which I think we should have missed.
You know, missing.
I talked about it kind of.
I'm create one and then have missed.
You bring it back to the board for formal approval.
I just want to get advice thoughts on it.
I think it'd be great.
Have it on the outside of just a council vote.
Because it's easy to say yes when you're excited about something.
But, you know, you can just write name and then maybe there's something they're qualified for.
So it is.
I think it'd be easy to be like that.
I don't want anybody to think that the ones that are being renamed aren't valid.
So probably should be a criteria.
Yeah.
Check the boxes.
I think it's a criteria.
I think that's everybody involved.
That way they can come back and say we fix somebody because of somebody we like.
Yeah.
with the criteria before he gets to you.
You know, I can't just say they have a big one, but some of the cool things I think they pointed out is they want to say going to serve at least 50 residents that would support this person.
They want to rate and constantly at least 25% of the owners that would be along that road to show their support.
And then they would like a rate and statement as to why this person deserves to be.
And so I just think that way it's just like you said.
People don't get excited when they name something and then we don't.
And a period of time.
And or you know.
And in order to fill out a bigger time to challenge.
There's no action on this.
Just to bring that make sure the board was.
Give it that some.
I like it.
Okay.
The nice.
Mayor's nomination took point Joe was elis.
To the mind of housing authority.
Turned it expire six three twenty eight.
Make up.
Jones.
Mark.
He's.
But.
Ten.
Jones.
Who.
Tone.
James.
The.
Five.
Sevan.
And.
Good morning.
You don't.
I mean I don't.
That's.
The.
To the.
That's not.
The.
To.
resource officers, and we inquired about the Chevy Tahoe.
It's the 2013 Chevy Tahoe.
I wouldn't just so everyone knows,
we've learned today that there are some significant
mechanical issues with the Tahoe.
It's overheat and that's all specifically that I know
is wrong with other than our mechanics,
that it has some significant issues with it.
Kevin Dunkle overheat sometimes too.
Thank you.
I'd call him power sergeant.
I think it's, I don't want to donate,
so I wouldn't want to donate something to a public school.
If it's going to break that on home,
and that causes any kind of hindrance to them responding to
the power sergeant.
I don't have a war in the heat of the weather
enough that it's safe here.
It's just pretty good when you get on the turn of the mic.
Right.
I talked to Joey today.
And the only thing they're going to use it for is more or less, for the officer to get to it from school,
and maybe take students to the sonic or something like that.
He's aware of some of the issues that it has, and the schools willing to still accept it and get it picked.
Second.
Jones.
Hi.
Hello.
How's the new business?
If any, which is the reasons of the focus of this agenda?
Today, we received the, um, how does the lean from the counter-traditional, the amended lean,
that accepted our 1-3rd, 2-3rd offer proposal on the Habermand property, and he has paid it,
so we'll be getting a check for $13,000.
That'll fix it.
Are you ready to?
Do you like money?
12 staff reports.
13 mayor council community announcements.
Yes.
Okay.
I want to, first I thank you, Chief, for everything that, on Saturday, we had a, everybody knows
that the answer is shooting on Main Street.
It was horrible to say the least.
And everybody come together.
The detectives, they did an outstanding job.
Everybody that was there did it.
The tribes come together.
And we just had a good showing.
And it really worked out real well in the end.
And it's still being investigated, but it's, it's good.
I want to thank the street department, Robert, Margaret, for answering my call right away
and setting up street barricades and getting the roads barricaded off.
And his crew, they've done an outstanding job.
And I also want to thank Valerie and Dispat.
She done an outstanding job, also.
It just, it was amazing to watch and see.
She didn't buy me breakfast because we was out till 6 o'clock in the morning.
He was hungry, but, you know, but hi, it was good.
We had a good.
It was, it was, for a bad situation everybody come together and it was awesome.
I want to thank everybody.
And the FH Chief, we got more updates from Tyler than ever before.
And that's still greatly appreciated.
It's comforting for us.
And the public has questions.
It's really nice.
The communication is greatly appreciated.
That's, I'll echo in part of whatever they said.
Great, great leadership.
I'm sorry that this had to be your welcoming, coming in party, but that's how we do it around here.
We break them in right.
But I appreciate your tenacity and I appreciate your willingness to
want to make our streets safer.
I will stand up against anybody who complains about police.
Presence.
I'd much rather answer those questions than a lack there.
I've got a few places you can look at too.
With the skeleton crew.
Yeah.
I was just going to reiterate.
I kind of got it out earlier with the, you know,
and I want to pile on to what they're saying.
I'm going to go a little different angle since they covered a lot of it.
What I heard from the community was things I have heard in a long time.
There's a lot of thank you for officers, which was refreshing.
Because a lot of what we hear about our officers is negative.
I heard great things from the owners of Mayabella.
The response time has officers were very cordial and very caring.
They appreciated the response time for sure.
I heard from a lady on B Street that said one of our officers when everything was going down.
She was in the front yard with her daughter.
And he said, man, please get you in your daughter inside.
Before you choose to go out with your daughter.
You make sure they were inside and safe.
I heard people talking about you.
And the fact that you were all the dudes who were in open, who were in transparent,
you were telling the community what you could tell them.
And I know there was, I know there's something to talk about there.
We got to forget that because most of those people don't understand what's going on or what they're allowed to know,
what they're not allowed enough.
I mean there are stuff that was going on that night that we weren't even allowed to know.
Because it was an investigation.
But I appreciate your leadership as they said.
I appreciate our officers.
In the fact that a lot of those negative Nancy's on social media.
If it was not a clock in mind.
And there was a suspect running fire and shots.
That wouldn't be chasing them.
They'd be high and under a table.
So thank you to your officers for taking care of our community.
It's not going to be unnoticed.
The changes are great.
And the community's loving it.
You ever select you that are just going to be them.
But the majority of the community is seeing it recognize and appreciate.
So thank you.
And separate note.
I have two other announcements.
One there is currently a board position open for these.
Sit us in more if anybody's interested or know if anybody would like to be on that preferably a member
I have a seat available
Also the Main Street dinner is this Friday evening. There is still take it's available to Main Street
Please try to get those seats filled. That's an excellent opportunity for our background town businesses and the Main Street program
See huge fundraising opportunity. They're also the accepting auction item. So if you know of anybody that has an item that would be interested in being auctioned off
There's already 27 items in this auction. So buy and take it to the dinner also allow you to participate in the auction
I don't think somebody take it. I can't wait to see that over there. It's going to be so much fun
So we do have one
We'll bring a picture of a firearm to the auction the actual item itself
It's just a picture
It's just a picture. I don't want to hear
Actually legally to give it away. We need to make sure they go to like a gun shop and do the
That's how it's going to be
And the person that donated it, they'll have to go pick up the firearm at the location to have the background check down. So the city's just reaping the rewards of that one
At the will the main street department calls me to have a spirit of credit and incredibly hard and her team Jesse I've borne everybody that was incredibly hard on these dinners
There's also the
Adaptability of change if they do get ringed out. We do have a plan. So don't put anybody panic about the frame music. It'll all be
Let's get some more of those take it. So five thirty
And it's being catered by
14 city manager communication. I just want to thank everybody for everything we did to make this budget happen
I mean everything that we've had recently done. I mean you guys pretty much covered all that but I feel like we're really like working together as a team
Staff and the board and I mean we'll have a common mission or she ain't through that mission
Thank you all
Thank you